Lorenzo Collection
Lorenzo Collection
1771-1956
8.0 linear feet, 20 reels microfilm
Correspondence, legal documents, financial records, and memorabilia concerning the Holland Land Company, Colonel John Lincklaen, Jonathan Denise Ledyard, Helen Ledyard Lincklaen, Jane Strawbridge Ledyard, other Ledyard and Lincklaen family members, and Lorenzo mansion in Cazenovia. Photocopies and microfilm only, no originals.
149140
Biographical History
In 1792, Colonel John Lincklaen, who was an agent for the Holland Land Company, came to central New York to see some of the company tracts of land. The present township of Cazenovia was included in that particular tract of land. Colonel Lincklaen made a temporary encampment at the foot of Cazenovia Lake and fell in love with the surrounding woods and valleys. A village was founded by Lincklaen on this spot and in 1807 he built the distinguished federal mansion pictured on the following page. He and his wife, the former Helen Ledyard of Aurora, had no children, but they adopted Mrs. Lincklaen's brother, Jonathan Denise Ledyard and made him their heir. After the death of Colonel Lincklaen, Jonathan Ledyard took over the management of the Holland Land Company's affairs and eventually purchased their interests and property. Jonathan married Miss Jane Strawbridge of Philadelphia and their eldest son was named Lincklaen Ledyard. In an attempt to perpetuate the name of the family benefactor, he had his name legally reversed to Ledyard Lincklaen, but his only child was a daughter, Helen Lincklaen, who married Charles S. Fairchild, the secretary of the treasury under President Grover Cleveland. On the death of Mrs. Fairchild in 1931, Lorenzo was willed to her cousin, Mrs. Eliphalet Remington who died in 1953, leaving it to her brother, George S. Ledyard, the present occupant with his son, John Ledyard.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Note: This collection consists entirely of photopies and microfilm. It contains no originals.
Lorenzo has remained in the possession of the Lincklaen/Ledyard family to the present day. Each generation of occupants used the various offices, vaults, files, and particularly attics for storage of family possessions and records. The documents enumerated in the Lorenzo Collection are the sum total of what has been preserved in Lorenzo since 1807 and represent almost two hundred years of family history. Quite naturally the thoughts and actions of the individuals characterize the preserved documents, but in an unusual fashion, the mansion Lorenzo has added its own peculiar stamp to the letters, diaries, and ledgers. Lorenzo has been the symbol of the family, its focal point, and its essence. All of the papers are related to it in one way or another and could be used by the diligent historian to fashion a "social, cultural, political, and economic history of Lorenzo in Cazenovia." As a recognition of its importance, Lorenzo has been honored by having the collection of documents named for it.
The families most strongly represented in the collection are:
Fairchild
Fitzhugh
Forman
Krumbhaar
Ledyard
Lincklaen
Remington
Seymour
Stebbins
Strawbridge
The collection is divided into thirteen series.
Holland Land Company Records contains company papers and the papers of four individuals: Theophile Cazenove, Arthur Cazenove, J. M. and Raoul de Cazenove.
John and Helen Lincklaen contains land, legal, and business papers as well as correspondence for John Linklaen and his wife, Helen Ledyard Linklaen.
Ledyard predecessors of John D. Ledyard contains personal and business papers of three Ledyard men, namely: John Ledyard of Hartford, John Ledyard the Traveller, and Benjamin Ledyard (father of John D. Ledyard)
John D. and Jane S. Ledyard contains the personal and business papers of John Denise Ledyard and his wife, Jane Strawbridge Ledyard. Also of interest are a few items of correspondence from Gerrit Smith, Samuel Morse, and Henry Ten Eyck.
The Sons of John D. Ledyard contains the personal and business papers of the four sons of Jonathan Denise Ledyard and their wives, namely: Lincklaen Ledyard and his wife Helen Seymour Ledyard; George Strawbridge Ledyard and his wife Anne Smith Ledyard; Fitzhugh Ledyard; and Lambertus Wolters Ledyard.
The Children of George S. Ledyard contains personal and business papers for Geroge Strawbridge Ledyard's three sons and one daughter, namely: John Denise Ledyard, Richard Fitzhugh Ledyard, Mary Fitzhugh Ledyard, and George S. Ledyard, Jr.
Samuel and Glen Ledyard contains the personal and business papers of John D. Ledyard's brother Samuel, and Samuel's son Glen Cuyler Ledyard.
M. R. Ledyard, Murray Ledyard contains both personal and business papers for these two men.
Allied and associated families includes personal and business papers of members of families related to or associated with the main Lorenzo family. Surnames represented are Breeze, Childs, Fairchild, Fitzhugh, Forman, Freneau, Krumbhaar, Remington, Seymour, Stebbins, Strawbridge, and Wolters.
Genealogies contains genealogies of various Lorenzo families. Surnames represented include Ledyard, Forman, Strawbridge, Gilpin, and Parker. The Strawbridge genealogy goes back to the 13th century. There is also research material on the name "Ledyard."
Ledyard miscellanea includes a cookbook, inventories, land surveys, and assorted other material from Ledyard family members.
Miscellaneous papers consists of assorted land and financial papers (bills, receipts, ledgers, title abstracts, land surveys, etc). Included here is a history of Cazenovia and documents relating to the Cherry Valley Turnpike.
Microfilm materials include personal diaries, travel accounts, letterbooks, farm ledgers, office diaries, and Holland Land Company records. This microfilming and photocopying project was sponsored by Syracuse University Library in cooperation with the late Dr. Albert B. Corey and the Division of Archives and History of the University of the State of New York. We regret that Dr. Corey did not live to see completion of this venture in which he was deeply concerned. Above all, a special note of thanks is extended for the generosity and courtesy of Messrs. George S. and John Ledyard. They permitted copying of these historically valuable papers and assisted in the sorting and identification of the documents. This finding aid could not have been constructed without their helpful advice, and the scholarly world is deeply in their debt.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series except microfilm are arranged alphabetically.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Forman, Samuel S., 1763-1860.; Lincklaen, John.; Ledyard, Jonathan Denise.; Lincklaen, Helen Ledyard.; Ledyard, Jane Strawbridge.; Ledyard family.; Lincklaen family.; Smith, Gerrit, 1797-1874.; Ten Eyck, Henry B.; Lorenzo Mansion (Cazenovia, New York); Holland Land Company.; Public land records -- New York (State); Business records -- New York (State); Family history.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Genealogies (histories); Indentures.; Land surveys.; Ledgers (account books); Wills.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Copies courtesy of Messrs. George S. Ledyard and John Ledyard.
Inventory
- Holland Land Company
  - Company papers
    - Powers of attorney, 1799-1824; 5 items (Box 1)
    - Indentures and related land papers, 1793-1831; 6 items (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous documents, undated; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Theophile Cazenove
    - Indentures to John Lincklaen, 1803; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Arthur Cazenove
    - Correspondence and related legal documents, 1819-1830; 15 items (Box 1)
  - J. M. and Raoul de Cazenove
    - Correspondence, 1875-1891; 9 items (Box 1)
- John and Helen Lincklaen
  - John Lincklaen
    - Land papers
      - Indentures to John Lincklaen, 1793-1797; 46 items (Box 1)
      - Indentures to John Lincklaen, 1798-1804; 32 items (Box 1)
      - Indentures to John Lincklaen, 1805-1818; 21 items (Box 1)
      - Indentures to John Lincklaen and Gerrit Boon from Simeon DeWitt, 1797; 27 items (Box 1)
      - Indentures from John Lincklaen, 1793-1797; 4 items (Box 2)
      - Indentures from John Lincklaen, 1799-1804; 16 items (Box 2)
      - Indentures from John Lincklaen, 1805-1818; 7 items (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous indentures, related to J. Lincklaen but not to or from him, 7 items (Box 2)
      - Surveys and maps, 4 items (Box 2)
      - Quit claims, 1802-1808; 2 items (Box 2)
      - Articles of agreement, 1793-1820; 22 items (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous deeds, 1807-1809; 3 items (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous land papers, 1800-1819; 18 items (Box 2)
    - Legal papers
      - Powers of attorney to John Lincklaen, 1790-1820; 14 items (Box 2)
      - List of debtors, undated; 1 item (Box 2)
      - Last will and testament, 1820; 1 item (Box 2)
      - Estate papers, 1818-1822; 3 items (Box 2)
      - Breach of Covenant: The Estate vs. Harvey and Underwood, 1818-1830; 3 items (Box 2)
    - Business papers
      - Documents related to roads, undated; 5 items (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous bills and receipts, 1794-1821; 49 items (Box 3)
      - Documents and correspondence related to the construction and repair of the Madison County Courthouse, 1810-1813; 45 items (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous business papers, 1807-1809; 3 items (Box 3)
      - Lorenzo Mansion papers, 1808-1842; 3 items (Box 3)
      - Farm papers and accounts, 1809-1817; 4 items (Box 3)
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence, 1803-1819; 12 items (Box 3)
      - To F. A. Van der Kemp, 1795; 1 item (Box 3)
      - To S. Forman, 1793; 1 item (Box 3)
      - To Holland Land Company, 1798-1812; 10 items (Box 3)
      - From J. J. Van der Kemp, 1809-1822; 11 items (Box 3)
      - From Paul Busti, 1810-1815; 10 items (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Meeting report, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
      - Militia clippings and correspondence, 1802; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Helen Ledyard Lincklaen (Mrs. John Lincklaen)
    - Land papers
      - Deed, 1804; 1 item (Box 3)
      - Indentures, 1825-1836; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Transfer to the Holland Land Company, undated; 1 item (Box 3)
    - Estate papers
      - Release on the John Lincklaen estate, 1836; 1 item (Box 3)
      - Wills and codicils, and related papers, 1840-1849; 4 items (Box 3)
      - Obituary, 1847; 1 item (Box 3)
- Ledyard predecessors
  - John Ledyard of Hartford
    - Last will and testament, 1771; 1 item (Box 3)
  - John Ledyard, the traveller
    - Diary and papers, 1773-1788; 1 item (Box 3)
    - Correspondence related the diary, 1921-1927; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Benjamin Ledyard
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming correspondence, 1794-1804; 2 items (Box 3)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1793-1804; 5 items (Box 3)
    - Financial papers
      - Promissory notes, 1792-1809; 5 items (Box 3)
      - Webster account, 1798-1806; 1 item (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1790-1804; 7 items (Box 3)
    - Land papers
      - Indentures, 1796-1803; 10 items (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous land papers, 1801-1803; 7 items (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Slave and servant indentures, 1784-1797; 6 items (Box 3)
      - Note relating to his family and a picture, 1 item (Box 3)
- John D. and Jane S. Ledyard
  - Jonathan Denise Ledyard
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming correspondence, 1820-1829 (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence, 1830-1849 (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence, 1850-1868 (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence, 1869-1874 (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from J. J. Van der Kemp, 1821-1853; 92 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from Cazenove family, 1823; 1836; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from Gerrit Smith, 1825-1865; 4 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from L. Mappa, 1822-1859; 10 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from Henry Ten Eyck, 1826; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from Samuel Morse, 1827; 1 item (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from Samuel Forman, 1836-1848; 32 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from James Seymour, 1828; 2 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from Charles Stebbins, 1828-1848; 3 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from William H. Seward, 1839-1840; 5 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from John A. Dix, 1842; 1 item (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from Sophia Ledyard, 1868-1874; 4 items (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence from George S. Ledyard, 1842; 1 item (Box 4)
      - Incoming correspondence relating to Wisconsin land purchases, 1862-1895; 16 items (Box 4)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1838-1871; 48 items (Box 5)
      - Letterbook, 1853-1855; 2 items (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence to Ledyard Lincklaen, 1848; 1 item (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence to Samuel Forman, 1845-1848; 8 items (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence to J. J. Van der Kemp, 1827-1855; 2 items (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence to J. C. Wolters, 1841; 1 item (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence to Helen Krumbhaar, 1865; 1 item (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence to H. C. S. Lincklaen, 1860; 1 item (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence to Sophia Ledyard, 1856-1865; 4 items (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence to Charles Stebbins, 1848; 1 item (Box 5)
      - Outgoing correspondence related to Cazenovia lake, 1849-1861; 11 items (Box 5)
      - Diary, 1840; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Land papers
      - Indentures to Jonathan Denise Ledyard, 1820-1835; 22 items (Box 6)
      - Indentures to Jonathan Denise Ledyard, 1836-1867; 52 items (Box 6)
      - Mortgage papers, 1835-1872; 22 items (Box 6)
      - Article of agreement, 1835-1873; 61 items (Box 6)
      - Deeds, quit-claims, warranty deeds, conveyances, 1858-1862; 7 items (Box 6)
      - Leases, 1842-1871; 8 items (Box 6)
      - U. S. Land Certificate and related papers, 1843; 5 items (Box 6)
      - Bonds, 1828-1857; 3 items (Box 6)
      - Indentures from Jonathan Denise Ledyard, 1822-1872; 17 items (Box 6)
      - Powers of attorney, 1821-1824; 4 items (Box 6)
      - Land accounts, 1860-1864; 3 items (Box 6)
      - Land papers and financial papers related to the village pier and fountain, 1854-1860; 19 items (Box 6)
      - Papers related to Indiana land purchases, 1821-1855; 4 items (Box 7)
      - Papers related to the Chicago wharf lot, 1856; 14 items (Box 7)
      - Papers related to Wisconsin land purchases, 1862-1879; 4 items (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous land papers, 1822-1858; 23 items (Box 7)
      - Papers related to Railroad leases and purchases, 1870; 5 items (Box 7)
    - Financial papers
      - Miscellaneous accounts, 1850-1870; 11 items (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous bills and receipts, 1819-1870; 174items (Box 7)
      - Tax and assessment papers, 1863-1865; 3 items (Box 7)
      - Stocks and bonds, 1840-1866; 5 items (Box 7)
      - Papers related to "Lorenzo", 1825-1826; 15 items (Box 7)
      - Promissory notes, 1838-1865; 22 items (Box 7)
      - Alexander Krumbhaar accounts, 1842; 1 item (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous papers
      - Business papers, 1833-1873; 5 items (Box 8)
      - Farm papers, 1856-1863; 133 items (Box 8)
      - Papers and documents related to his dispute with Henry Ten Eyck, 1856-1860; 7 items (Box 8)
      - Legal papers, 1829-1850; 3 items (Box 8)
      - Duplicate office file, undated; 1 item (Box 8)
    - Estate papers
      - Appraisal and inventory, 1874; 5 items (Box 8)
      - Legal and financial papers, 1875-1889; 8 items (Box 8)
      - Last will and testaments, 1837-1838; 3 items (Box 8)
      - Letters of condolence, 1874; 53 items (Box 8)
      - Obituary and clippings, 1874; 2 items (Box 8)
      - Estate correspondence, 1878; 1 item (Box 8)
      - Estate land papers, 1874-1886; 27 items (Box 8)
  - Jane Strawbridge Ledyard (Mrs. Jonathan Denise Ledyard)
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence, 1819-1851; 3 items (Box 8)
      - Incoming correspondence from Helen Strawbridge, 1804-1807; 7 items (Box 8)
      - Incoming correspondence from Thomas Gilpin, 1852; 3 items (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Newspaper notice of her death, 1855; 1 item (Box 8)
- Sons of John D. Ledyard
  - Lincklaen Ledyard (his name was later reversed by an act of the legislature)
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming correspondence, 1845-1861; 6 items (Box 9)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1848-1858; 15 items (Box 9)
      - Correspondence with Henry Krumbhaar, 1861-1864; 2 items (Box 9)
      - Correspondence with George S. Ledyard, 1841-1855; 2 items (Box 9)
      - Correspondence with Samuel Forman, 1846-1847; 7 items (Box 9)
      - Correspondence with Cazenove, 1813-1816 (Box 9)
      - Correspondence related to the Barge canal, 1849-1862; 14 items (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Indentures, 1845-1847; 2 items (Box 9)
      - Land papers, undated; 1 item (Box 9)
      - Financial papers, 1863; 3 items (Box 9)
      - Legal contracts, 1847-1850; 2 items (Box 9)
      - Papers related to the Barge canal, 1847-1852; 5 items (Box 9)
  - Helen Seymour Ledyard (Mrs. Lincklaen Ledyard)
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming correspondence, 1870-1893; 3 items (Box 9)
      - Leases to the Syracuse, Ontario and New York Railway, 1882-; 3 Items (Box 9)
  - George Strawbridge Ledyard
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming correspondence, 1839-1859; 35 items (Box 9)
      - Incoming correspondence, 1860-1891; 172 items (Box 9)
      - Incoming correspondence from Horatio Seymour, 1870-1880; 4 items (Box 9)
      - Incoming correspondence from Bragg, Conlay and Company, 1852-1854; 24 items (Box 9)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1852-1890; 17 items (Box 9)
      - Outgoing correspondence to Bragg, Conley and Company, 1852-1853; 3 items (Box 9)
      - Outgoing correspondence to Lincklaen Ledyard, 1846; 1 item (Box 9)
    - Land papers
      - Indentures to George Strawbridge Ledyard, 1862-1885; 9 items (Box 10)
      - Indentures from George Strawbridge Ledyard, 1872-1888; 10 items (Box 10)
      - Mortgage papers, 1879-1890; 11 items (Box 10)
      - Deeds and title papers, 1879-1891; 7 items (Box 10)
      - Survey, 1876; 1 item (Box 10)
    - Financial papers
      - Miscellaneous bills and receipts, 1852-1890; 296items (Box 10)
      - Promissory notes, 1863-1889; 6 items (Box 10)
      - Stock certificates, 1870-1872; 2 items (Box 10)
      - Account books, 1882; 2 items (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous papers
      - Partnership papers, 1870; 4 items (Box 10)
      - Papers related to the Cazenovia Public Library, 1890; 2 items (Box 10)
      - Invitations, undated (Box 10)
      - Papers related to the European trip, 1883-1886; 101 items (Box 10)
      - Bills and receipts related to the European trip, 1884-1886; 170 items (Box 10)
      - Brigade order, 1854; 1 item (Box 10)
    - Estate papers
      - Estate account book, 1890-1891; 1 item (Box 11)
      - Land papers, 1891-1892; 2 items (Box 11)
      - Insurance papers, 1890-1891; 2 items (Box 11)
      - Obituary, 1890; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Anne Smith Fitzhugh Ledyard (Mrs. George S. Ledyard)
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming correspondence, 1880-1892; 9 items (Box 11)
      - Letters of condolence upon the death of her husband, 125 items (Box 11)
  - Lambertus Wolters Ledyard
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming correspondence, 1863-1894; 42 items (Box 11)
      - Outgoing correspondence, 1862-1890; 5 items (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Land papers, 1878-1898; 4 items (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1864-1871; 5 items (Box 11)
- Children of George S. Ledyard
  - John Denise Ledyard
    - Incoming correspondence, 1890; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Richard Fitzhugh Ledyard
    - Correspondence, 1884-1891; 8 items (Box 11)
  - Mary Fitzhugh Ledyard
    - Correspondence
      - Outgoing correspondence to Helle, 1885-1886; 13 items (Box 11)
      - Outgoing correspondence to mother, 1889; 1 item (Box 11)
  - George Strawbridge Ledyard, Jr.
    - Correspondence
      - Outgoing correspondence to his family, 1888-1889; 8 items (Box 11)
      - Incoming letters from his father, 1884-1888; 4 items (Box 11)
- Samuel and Glen Ledyard
  - Samuel Ledyard
    - Correspondence
      - Outgoing correspondence to his brother Jonathan Denise Ledyard, 1824-1847; 7 items (Box 11)
      - Correspondence with his daughter Helen Ann L. L. Krumbhaar, 1847; 2 items (Box 11)
    - Financial papers
      - Miscellaneous financial papers, undated; 4 items (Box 11)
      - Ledger, 1822; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Glen Cuyler Ledyard
    - Note, undated; 1 item (Box 11)
- M. R. Ledyard, Murray Ledyard
  - M. R. Ledyard
    - Correspondence, 1884; 1 item (Box 11)
  - Murray Ledyard
    - Correspondence, 1907; 1 item (Box 11)
- Allied and associated families
  - Breeze, Mrs. Helen Burrows
    - Autobiographical sketch, 1860; 1 item (Box 12)
  - Childs, Perry G.
    - Correspondence and papers, 1810-1854; 6 items (Box 12)
  - Fairchild, Charles S.
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence, 1889-1917; 11 items (Box 12)
      - Correspondence with George D. Krumbhaar, 1867-1894; 11 items (Box 12)
    - Legal papers
      - Papers related to the school district controversy, 1914-1916; 9 items (Box 12)
      - Last will and testament and codicils, 1920-1923; 1 item (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Printed articles and reports, 1875-1914; 4 items (Box 12)
      - Newspaper clippings on his career and his death, 88 Items (Box 12)
  - Fairchild, Helen Ledyard
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence, 1880-1888; 7 items (Box 12)
      - Correspondence and papers related to her book on Francis Adrian Van der Kemp, 1903-1904; 102 items (Box 12)
      - Correspondence and papers related to the family cemeteries in Cazenovia and Aurora, 1924-1925; 18 items (Box 12)
      - Correspondence and papers related to property at Cazenovia Lake, Chittenango Falls and the Village Park, 1921-1929; 38 items (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous legal correspondence and papers, 1917-1930; 12 items (Box 12)
      - Correspondence and papers related to the Woman suffrage movement, 1910-1914; 11 items (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Will and estate papers, 1929-1931; 2 items (Box 12)
      - Printed materials related to the Woman suffrage movement, 1894-1915; 21 items (Box 12)
  - Fitzhugh, Mary Anne
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1872-1882; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Fitzhugh, Richard P.
    - Legal papers, 1835-1856; 12 items (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Correspondence, 1855; 1 item (Box 13)
      - Financial papers, 1843-1845; 10 items (Box 13)
  - Forman, Jonathan
    - Revolutionary War papers, 1777-1783; 17 items (Box 13)
  - Forman, Samuel
    - Correspondence
      - Letterbook, 1796-1799; 19 items (Box 13)
      - Correspondence with John Lincklaen, 13 items (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1788-1807; 19 items (Box 13)
    - Business papers
      - Business agreements and related papers, 1776-1802; 40 items (Box 13)
      - Post office account, 1799-1802; 34 items (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Indentures and related land documents, 1787-1822; 15 items (Box 13)
      - Autobiography, memoirs, 5 items (Box 13)
      - Military papers, 1793-1802; 32 items (Box 13)
  - Freneau, Eleanor Forman
    - Correspondence, 1793-1795; 2 Items (Box 13)
  - Krumbhaar, Helen Ledyard
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence, 1833-1872; 11 items (Box 14)
      - Correspondence with Alexander Krumbhaar, 1840; 6 items (Box 14)
      - Correspondence related to her marriage settlement, 1842-1843; 9 items (Box 14)
    - Legal papers
      - Documents related to the marriage settlement, 1840-1842; 4 items (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous legal papers, 1840-1866; 2 items (Box 14)